

## MARTINA ARESCO

#### ABOUT ME

I am a Communication and Digital Marketing Specialist, managing the communication and digital marketing activities of my company and clients. My skills also include press office activities, public relations and event organisation. I have worked mainly with clients from the fashion, hospitality and food & beverage sectors, developing tailor-made communication strategies and building strong media relations.

#### CONTACT

Date of birth: 30/03/1994 Nationality: Italian

Address: Via Giovanni Sercambi 53, 50133, Florence (FI)

Phone Number: 377 3075641 Email: martinaarescoelive.it

#### LANGUAGES

Italian (Native speaker) English (B2) Spanish (B2) French (B2)

#### EXPERTISE AND SKILLS

Communication
Digital Marketing
Public Relations
Press Office
Event Planning
Social Media Manager
Influencer Marketing
Team Working

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

### Trade and Digital Marketing Specialist

GREAT LENGTHS (16/09/2024 - Present)

- Communication and Digital Marketing specialist: Management of the company's communication and digital marketing activities and development of targeted marketing and communication consulting packages for clients;
- Social Media Management: Supervision and content creation of the company's Italian social media profiles and social media consulting for clients; Strategic consulting: Targeted brand
- positioning strategies for clients;
  - Influencer Marketing & PR: relations and managing collaborations with influencers and talent;
- Event Organisation: Planning and execution of events and special projects.

#### Senior Account Executive

PRCO (13/02/2023 - 19/06/2024)

- Press Office and PR: Management of relationships with press, influencers, and target clients; organization of press trips and visits; coordination of interviews, editorials, and projects to promote brand visibility;
- Strategic Consultancy: Development of targeted brand positioning strategies for clients;
- Event Organization: Planning and execution of events and special projects, including launches, openings, cocktail parties, and press days, with follow-up activities. Creation and management of press mailing lists, as well as outreach to influencers, celebrities, and socialities.

#### **PR & Communication Account**

ALLUMEUSE COMMUNICATION (26/08/2022 - 08/02/2023)

- Press Office and PR: Management of relationships with press, influencers, and target clients; organization of press trips and visits; coordination of interviews, editorials, and projects to promote brand visibility;
- Strategic Consultancy: Development of targeted brand positioning strategies for clients;
- Event Organization: Planning and execution of events and special projects, including launches, openings, cocktail parties, and press days, with follow-up activities. Creation and management of press mailing lists, as well as outreach to influencers, celebrities, and socialites.

#### PR & Communication Account

GM/PR CONSULTING (28/03/2021 - 12/08/2022)

- Press Office and PR: Management of relationships with press, influencers, and target clients; organization of press trips and visits; coordination of interviews, editorials, and projects to promote brand visibility;
- Strategic Consultancy: Development of targeted brand positioning strategies for clients:
- Social Media Management: Defining communication strategies and creating digital content for clients collaborating with influencers, acting as the agency's Social Media Manager;
- Event and Fashion Show Organization: Planning, organizing, and supervising fashion shows; conceptualizing and managing events and special projects, including launches, openings, cocktail parties, and press days, with comprehensive follow-up. Creating and maintaining mailing lists for press, influencers, celebrities, and socialites.

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

#### Master in Management della Moda e del Lusso

RCS ACADEMY (2020 - 2021)

- Insight into the Fashion and Luxury Industry: Gained a comprehensive understanding of the sector through coursework and practical experiences;
- **Teamwork Projects:** Developed strategic and communication plans for the Borbonese brand. Worked on the launch and communication strategy for the fragrance "L'Eau d'Issey" by Issey Miyake;
- Industry Expert Testimonials: Engaged with insights and knowledge shared by professionals from the fashion and luxury industry;
- Additional Skills: Completed courses in Excel and advanced English language.

# Bachelor's Degree in Performing Arts and Communication UNIVERSITY OF PISA (2016 - 2020)

ONIVERSITI OT FISA (2010 - 2020

• **Passing Grade**: 108/110

#### Diploma Languages

FRANCESCO CECIONI HIGH SCHOOL (2008 - 2013)

• English, French and Spanish languages.

#### INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

- *Travel: I* have travelled extensively, both in Italy and abroad, enriching my personal and professional baggage, thanks also to work experience.
- **Fashion:** Fashion has always been one of my greatest passions, which led me to attend the Master in Fashion and Luxury Management. This path allowed me to delve into the sector with a formative approach, enriched by expert testimony.
- **Photography:** I had the opportunity to delve into photography during my university studies, thanks to a dedicated course.
- Social Media: I am passionate about social media and currently also hold the role of Social Media Manager, combining creativity and strategy in content management.
- Art: Another great passion of mine: in my spare time I like to visit exhibitions and museums, enriching my cultural background.
- **Dance:** I practised ballet and modern dance from the age of 4 to 16, an experience that taught me dedication and creativity.